#### Carlos K. Martos

(918) 734-6931

<u>carloskmartos@gmail.com</u> <u>https://csharpfiasco.github.io</u> <u>github.com/csharpfiasco</u>

Tulsa, OK 74137

## **Summary:**

I have emphasized people and clients throughout my career. I enjoy learning from my peers and I enjoy teaching junior employees. My background has involved refactoring Classic ASP and VB.NET projects into modern solutions. I have experience with ReactJS, JavaScript and the Microsoft stack (.NET, C#, TSQL).

#### **Skills:**

- Languages: SQL/TSQL,.C#/NET Core, VB/.NET, HTML/CSS, JavaScript (ES5/6), Python
- Software: SQL Server Management Studio, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Django, Tensorflow/Keras, Photoshop, Illustrator, Microsoft Office
- Libraries: ReactJS, Tailwind, jQuery, Bootstrap

#### **Education:**

University of Tulsa

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science – 2017

# **Projects:**

- As technical lead at Techsico, I oversaw and worked on the refactor of a legacy VB.NET system into a ReactJS web app (with Tailwind CSS) with a .NET Core back end.
- As lead developer (three-person team), I built a custom distribution system, including ordering, client management, order management, purchase order, credit, revenue-reporting systems.
- As a personal project I built a web crawler and screenshot Windows service in .net using Selenium.
- I developed a quick-reporting system in .NET to streamline report page builds, including Excel exports.
- At Spherexx, I developed and maintained a payment gateway using the Square API in vbScript.

#### **Research Experience:**

#### University of Tulsa

• Student Researcher

12/2015 - 04/2016

- Research involved utilizing information foraging techniques to better understand how to improve human-information interaction in repositories with reusable code, specifically MATLAB and App Inventor
- Categorized interactions between user programmers and search gallery interfaces, analyzing patterns in behavior and helpful cues

## Work:

#### Spherexx

9142 S. Sheridan Rd. Tulsa, OK 74137

09/2017 - 08/2020

- Full Stack Developer
- Lead Developer
- Build and maintain liquor and cannabis distribution systems
- Custom reporting (gross profit, sales, depletion, OTC)
- Employee, client, product management, cart and ordering systems
- Long-term growth analysis
- Sales dashboards
- Custom websites and content management systems

## Carlos K. Martos

(918) 734-6931

<u>carloskmartos@gmail.com</u> <u>https://csharpfiasco.github.io</u> github.com/csharpfiasco

Tulsa, OK 74137

#### Techsico

910 S. Hudson Ave. Tulsa, OK 74112

08/2020 - 03/2021

- Technical Lead and Lead Developer
- Hiring manager primarily responsible for hiring team
- Project management with Jira
- Product architect responsible for the refactor of the enterprise resource planning web app
- Responsible for training of junior developers
- Used Elastic Beanstalk to host .NET Core API and legacy vb.NET application
- Used AWS Amplify to host websites with continuous integration
- Lead developer for React front end and .NET Core back end
- Managed legacy python applications
- Experience with Open ID (OIDC)

# QuikTrip

4705 S 129th E Ave. Tulsa, OK 74134

03/2021 - Current

- Software Developer II
- Web development with ASP.NET and Angular
  - o Entity Framework
  - o OData
  - Swagger/Swashbuckle
  - o XUnit
- ETL development with SSIS
- Database design with SQL Server
- Windows Services with .NET 6

#### **Leadership/Organizations:**

Society of Hispanic Professional Engineers (SHPE)

• Public Relations Chair

06/2015 - 06/2016

- Helped advertise TU-SHPE and planning projects and events; attended National Institute for Leadership Advancement (NILA)
- Founding President

09/2014 - 06/2015

• Organized professional events, inviting companies to visit the University of Tulsa and increased our budget for the next year by 66%; attended regional conference

# Carlos K. Martos

(918) 734-6931

carloskmartos@gmail.com https://csharpfiasco.github.io github.com/csharpfiasco

Tulsa, OK 74137